

## Janick Weberpals, RPh, Ph.D. Health Data Scientist

Born 1989 in Germany, current location: Boston, MA

janickweberpals.github.io

+1 (857) 381-7865 LinkedIn profile

janick.weberpals@me.com

## About me ———

I'm a healthcare data scientist with 8+ years of experience in the design and analysis of large healthcare databases studies in both industry and academia. I'm passionate about the integration of various data modalities (EHR/EMR, imaging, NLP, claims) using deep learning to solve real-world problems in healthcare and causal inference. In addition, I have deep domain knowledge in the fields of cancer and cardiovascular diseases. I have (co-) authored 20+ peer-reviewed methodological and clinical publications and received several awards.

# Skills ———

R

Python

Tensorflow, Keras

LETEX, Markdown

HPC, SLURM, Unix

SOL

SAS

Education

2018-2020 **Postdoctoral Fellowship** Data Science, Roche Innovation Center, Germany Deep learning on electronic health record (EHR) data

2015-2018 **Ph.D. Epidemiology** Medical Faculty, Heidelberg University, Germany Graduated with *Summa cum laude* honors

2015-2018 **Board certification** Bavarian Chamber of Pharmacists, Munich, Germany Specialized Pharmacist in Drug Information

2010-2015 **Registered Pharmacist** College of Pharmacy, Marburg University, Germany *Pharmaceutical Sciences (PharmD equivalent)* 

### Professional Experience

2022- Instructor in Medicine Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA Faculty at Harvard Medical School leading innovative projects to combine routinely collected healthcare data (EHR/EMR, imaging, NLP, claims) to study and generate high-quality comparative effectiveness and safety of medical interventions.

2022- Investigator Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA, USA Working on NIH and FDA-funded projects to leverage large, federated healthcare databases for medical evidence generation.

2020-2022 **Data Scientist** Hoffmann-La Roche/Genentech, Basel, Switzerland Awarded "Exceptional Performance" in 2021. Led and collaborated in cross-functional teams to implement and validate ML/NLP algorithms and real-world database studies which supported and expedited clinical teams with regulatory drug applications in oncology and neuroscience. Contributed to R package development which increased speed and validity of real-world evidence projects.

2018-2020 **Postdoctoral Fellow in Deep Learning on EHR** Roche, Munich, Germany Implemented deep learning methods to analyze large electronic health record (EHR) databases which supported protocol design and strategic decision making in single-arm clinical trials.

2015-2018 **Doctoral Researcher** German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg, Germany Analysis of large oncological database linkages by partnering with international cancer registries which resulted in 14 high-impact publications used for national public health & cancer survival surveillance.

2014-2015 **Research Scholar** University of Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA Contributed to a multidisciplinary project to develop a *predictive* risk model to identify and prevent adverse events among hospitalized patients. The model was implemented and tested in a few US hospitals.

#### Selected Awards & Honors

2018 Stephan-Weiland Award (German Society for Epidemiology)

Advancement Award for best Ph.D. thesis in Epidemiology (German

Association for Medical Informatics, Biometry and Epidemiology)

2017 Poster Award (Helmholtz International Graduate School)

2016 & 17 International Society for Pharmacoepidemiology (ISPE) Scholarship

Selected publications (full list: janickweberpals.github.io/publications)

<u>Weberpals J</u>, Becker T, Schmich F, Ruettinger D, Theis FJ, Bauer-Mehren A. Deep learning-based propensity scores for confounding control in comparative effectiveness research: a large-scale real-world data study. **Epidemiology** (2021).

Loureiro H, Becker T, Bauer-Mehren A, Ahmidi N, Weberpals J. Artificial Intelligence for Prognostic Scores in Oncology: a benchmarking study. **Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence** (2021).